拿那么多酸奶干什么
What's with all the yogurt?
嘘 德卡斯一直私自开我的储物柜
Shh! Durkas has been breaking into my locker.
但我想出了一个复仇计划
But I've got a little revenge planned.
不好意思 我其实没兴趣知道
Sorry. I just remembered I don't really care.
妈妈呢 噢 天呐 你穿的是什么
Where's Mom? Oh, my God, what is that outfit?
你不会要走哥特路线吧
Are you going goth?
你现在还抱着毛绒熊猫睡觉呢
You still sleep with a stuffed panda.
你滚去参加大学联谊会吧
Don't you have a fraternity to pass out in?
你那个小手术 还需要点什么东西吗
Is there anything else you need for your procedure?
我想来点冰激凌
Um, I think I'm supposed to have ice cream.
是吗 可我觉得...
Hmm. Actually, I don't--
不好意思 到底是切你的输卵管
I'm sorry. Is it a vasecto-you,
还是切我的输精管
Or a vasectomy?
-到时给你买个冰激凌 -谢谢
- You can have ice cream. - Thanks.
-今天...-要切个东东
- Today... - Snip-a-dee-doo-dah!
我们讨论了有段日子了
We-we've been talking about doing this for a while.
没错 没错 自从爸和歌洛莉亚
Yeah. Yeah, ever since dad and Gloria
不小心搞出个孩子
had their little accident,
我们不需要那种惊喜了
we don't need any surprises.
而且
Also, though,
以后在闺房中也可以多一些"自由发射"
it will allow for a little more freestylin' in the boudoir
因为不必再担心搞出个小生命出来
If we're not having to worry about adding more critters.
更重要的是
More importantly,
那是我们五年计划的关键部分
it is an essential part of our 5-year plan.
噢 五年计划 跟他们说说罗斯夫妇吧
Oh, the 5-year plan. Talk about the--the Rosses.
罗斯夫妇 好吧
The Rosses--okay,
罗斯夫妇是我们的老朋友
the Rosses are this couple we have known forever, and...
他们生不了小孩
They were never able to have kids,
-所以我们对他们有点... -嫉妒
- So we always felt a little... - jealous of them.
我们很爱我们的孩子
I mean, we love our kids,
但约翰和克丽希有时间旅行
But John and Chrissy can travel...
他们的皮肤长年是健康的棕色
They're always tan.
你看得出克丽希比我大8岁吗
Did you know that Chrissy is eight years older than me?
要我说 她比你年轻8岁还差不多
I would have said eight years younger.
她身上迸发出的青春火花...
There's just this spark in her that--
真是 瞧瞧我身边的这位 你以前也有的
Well, look who I'm talking to. You used to have it.
-你好像没...听到我说 -我要说的是
- Wow. It's like you don't... hear... - The point is,
只要我们不再造个新人
As long as we don't have another baby,
5年后我们也可以享受那样的生活
That life is ours in five years
到时候卢克已经离家上大学了
When Luke goes off to college.
或者别的地方
Or somewhere.
我今天其实是开开心心地去医生那儿的
It will actually be a pleasure walking into that doctor's office today
你终于来了 妈
There you are. Mom--
等等 你这是什么行头
Hang on a second. What is this?
是受了你那位叫斯凯勒的朋友的影响吗
Is this because of your new friend Skyler?
她正努力改变形象
Oh, she's just trying to change her image.
顺便说下 挺有成效的
Nice work, by the way.
你已经从呆瓜升级到呆鸭了
You went from dork to Count Dorkula.
能聊聊我的衣服吗 我早就让你寄过来的
Can we talk about my clothes? You were supposed to send them!
我等会儿再说你的事 等一下
I'll be with you in a second. Hang on.
我不喜欢那个斯凯勒
I don't like this Skylar.
你不必非得改变自己
You don't need to change who you are
来迎合那些酷小孩
to fit in with the cool kids.
她当然得变了 她实在是太土了
Oh, of course she does. She just is so uncool,
她都分不清谁是酷小孩
she doesn't know who the cool kids are.
你难道不要忙着挂科吗
Don't you have a class to fail?
你不需要去训练乌鸦吗[哥特风]
Don't you have a raven to train?
听着 我这周强调了两遍衣服的事儿
Listen, I have repeated outfits twice this week.
-我受不了了 -我明天会替你解决的
- It's a disaster. - And I will deal with it tomorrow,
但今天我要带你爸去见医生
But today I'm taking your father to the doctor.
-他要做个屁股切除术 -什么
- He's having an ass-ectomy. - What?
-我耳朵很灵的 -你要切扁挑体吗
- I hear things. - You're getting your tonsils out?
我看我们家需要来个"笨蛋切除术"
Ohh! This family needs a dumbass-ectomy.
闭嘴 你总以为自己多...
Oh, shut up! I'm tired of you thinking you're so...
爸没跟你说过你其实是被领养的吗
Did dad ever tell you you were adopted?
-不 我才不是 -再忍五年
- No, I wasn't! - Five more years.
好的
Okay.
好吧 那么放学后
Okay, so after school,
你和朋友艾希莉去游泳
You're going to your friend Ashley's to swim,
所以我要你现在去准备你的泳衣
So I'm gonna need you to go get your swimsuit,
你的泳镜还有防晒油 好吗
Your swim goggles, and your sunscreen, okay?
然后换个没粘猫毛的衣服
And change into a dress that's not covered in cat fur.
那猫掉毛掉的厉害
Oh, that cat is really losing its hair.
或许我们该给它抹点你的防脱发剂
Maybe we should slip it one of your propecia, huh?
什么防脱发剂
What propecia?
你的防...
Your pro--
那不是我们...
Is that not something that we're...
所以 你今天打算做什么
So, uh, what you got going on today?
忙 忙 忙得抓狂
Ohh. Busy, busy, busy, busy.
我可能得买些灯泡 然后时间允许的话
I might buy some light bulbs, and then, if time permits,
我也许要继续搞我的大项目
I might do a little work on my master project.
绝密哦
Top secret.
-可别问我那是什么 -我不会问啦
- So don't you dare ask what it is. - I won't.
自从莉莉上了幼儿园
Since Lily started kindergarten,
小卡有了很多空闲时间
Cam's had a lot of free time.
我想劝他找个工作 但是
Now, I-I'd like to suggest he go back to work, but...
有历史为鉴 那是个敏感的话题
Historically, uh, that has proved to be a sensitive topic.
我们去年夏天给越南那边递交了领养材料
We sent those adoption papers to vietnam last summer.
不 感谢你才对
No, thank you very much,
请将重点放在我的语气上 而不是用词上
And please remember my tone, not my words.
她说领养宝宝要九个月的时间
She said it could take up to nine months to get a baby.
太不人道了
It's inhuman!
是吗 别...我知道这很令人沮丧
Is it? Don't-- I-I know it's frustrating,
但或许 与其把自己搞得神经兮兮
But maybe instead of driving yourself crazy
傻等着电话铃响 你不如重返工作岗位
Waiting for the phone to ring, you could go back to work.
你说什么
Excuse me?
去找份工作
Get a job!
不 那会将你的注意力从宝宝身上移开
No, it--it'll help you take your mind off the baby.
怎么 因为我是个大块头吃白食的吗
Oh, what, because I'm a big, giant freeloader?
其实 我觉得我已经把原因说得很清楚了
Actually, I think I laid out the reasons pretty clearly.
不 我觉得你将我定性为懒到骨子里的人
No, I think you pegged me. Bone lazy,
就像当年在农场 每天第一个上床
Just like on the farm-- first to bed,
早上最后一个起床
last to wake up in the morning.
话说 不如你打电话给我爸
You know what? Why don't you call my dad,
你们两个彻夜长谈一番
And you two can gab all night
尽情笑话我是个吃白食的懒汉
about what a teet-sucking layabout I am?
好吧 我觉得我可能搅痛了
Okay, I think I might have paddled
你心里陈年的旧伤疤
into some deeper waters here.
怎么 你以为我整天闲坐着吗
What, you think I sit around all day?
我现在就不坐了
Well, I'm not sitting now.
什么情况
What's happening?
你早已经打好包了吗
You keep a packed suitcase?
真是个健康的宝宝
That's a healthy baby.
-稍等 -怎么了
- Hold on. - What?
那是个车牌和毂盖吗
Is that a license plate and a hubcap?
就像电影《大白鲨》里那样
You know, like in "Jaws"?
我从来没看过
I never saw it.
我倒是看过 但我不记得
I saw it, but I don't remember
有孕妇怀了个车毂盖的场景啊
a scene with a hubcap in a pregnant woman.
算了
Ah, forget it.
你们想知道怀的是男孩还是女孩吗
So, would you like to know if you're having a boy or a girl?
-是的 -不想
- Yes. - No.
我希望到时候能有个惊喜
Ay. I want it to be a surprise,
你不想吗 杰
Don't you, Jay?
我65岁高龄再次喜当爹
I'm having a baby at 65.
你还想再来点惊喜吗 歌洛莉亚
You want another surprise, Gloria?
自己去买一袋玉米片吧[内含各种惊喜小玩具]
Buy yourself a box of cracker jacks.
该死的干洗店
Estupid dry cleaners!
把我的衣服都弄缩水了
They shrink my clothes!
或许你该穿孕妇装了
Might be time for maternity wear.
你疯了吗 我都没显肚子
Are you crazy? I'm barely showing.
亲爱的 你怀孕前 衣服就被大胸撑爆了啊
Sweetheart, your shirts barely fit before you were pregnant.
我可没听你抱怨过太大啊
And I never heard you complain.
我们需要一条长一点的裤带
We're gonna need a bigger belt.
给力啊
Come on.
好难哦
This is hard.
嘿 小卡
Hey, Cam.
谁饿了呀
Who's hungry?
哎呀呀 你是想过来一起吃饭吧
Ohh! Were you thinking about dropping by for lunch...
又来啊
Again?
我真希望我有空
You know, I-I really wish I could,
但这里现在忙得一团乱
But it's, uh, it's a zoo around here.
但是 那个 小卡
Um... but, hey, Cam--
小卡 你能不能去朗吉娜的时装店
Cam, would you mind, uh, stopping by Longinus' boutique
替我买几件衬衫啊
And picking up a few shirts for me?
-当然可以 -谢啦
- Sure. - Thank you.
或者我们可以一起去
Or we can do it together.
-是你啊 -是我啊
- Hey! - Hey!
-你来了 -我来了
- Hi. - Hi.
-你还好吗 -很好
- How are you? - Good.
好吧
Okay.
那 那很好 好吧
Um... that's-- that's good. Okay. Yeah.
你没把我的绿夹克寄来吗
You didn't send the little green jacket?!
亲爱的 我可不想又遭一次罪
Honey, I am not doing this again.
我之前寄那个包裹就花了一小时
It took me an hour to mail that package before.
我患有"邮局"创伤"后"应激障碍症
I have post-post office traumatic stress disorder.
别奸笑了 不怎么有水平
Stop smiling. It's not that clever.
很有水平的好吧
It is clever,
反正我今天是死也不会再回去了
and there's no way I'm going back there today.
天啊 我恨死你了
Oh, my God, I hate you so much!
抱歉 你爸打电话来了 我得挂了
Oh, sorry, that's your father. Gotta go!
克莱尔 你在哪儿
Claire, where are you?
亲爱的 我刚刚在邮局的经历糟糕透了
Oh, honey, I just had a hellish experience at the post office.
我患有"邮局"创伤"后"应激障碍症
I have post-post office traumatic stress disorder.
-真经典 -好棒
- Nailed it. - Yes!
卢克忘了带他的科学作业
And Luke forgot his science project,
所以我现在给他送到学校去
So now I'm at the school dropping it off.
那我在诊所的预约怎么办
Um, but what about my appointment?
真抱歉 亲爱的 我替你做了其他安排
I'm so sorry, honey. I made other arrangements,
但我保证 你醒过来的时候我会在你身边
but I promise I will be there when you wake up.
安排
Arrangements?
等下 等下 等下 等下
What--um... wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
什么安排
What--what arrangements?
我 我私心想着你能带我去是最好了
I, um... I kinda wanted you to take me.
走吧 跺跺脚 快快跑
Let's go! Chop, chop!
不是吧你 非要用"剁"吗
Seriously? "Chop, chop"?
噢对哦
Oh, right.
靠 搞毛啊
Ohh! What?
这是什么
What is this?
-妈 -卢克
- Mom? - Luke!
你在干什么呢
What are you doing?!
我替你把科学作业送过来
I was dropping off your science project.
别送到我的储物柜里啊
Not to my locker!
你什么时候才能不丢我的脸啊
When are you ever gonna stop embarrassing me?
再忍五年
Five more years.
我的天呐
Oh, my god!
如果你还要继续高八度
If you're gonna go any higher,
我还是放下杯子免得被你喊炸了
Maybe I should put this down, huh?
怎么样 有看中的不
So? What do you think?
终于有家店卖的衬衫
Finally, a store that sells shirts
是我们男人想穿的了
men actually wanna wear.
谢谢你 需要我就喊一声
Thank you. Look, holla if you need me.
今天人手不太够
We're a little shorthanded today.
杰玛库斯人呢
What happened to J'Marcus?
别提了 她是个混乱狂
Don't ask. She's a J'Mess.
跟你说 太难找到
I'm telling you, it is so hard to find someone
既懂服装又善于和人打交道的员工了
who knows clothes and is good with people.
真希望我有人选可以推荐
Well, I wish I knew somebody.
我的老天 等等 小卡
Oh, my god. Wait a second. Cam?
你不会想试试这份工作吧
You wouldn't think about taking the job, would you?
你知道你有多合适吗
Do you realize how perfect you'd be?
那当然了 但我...
Well, yes. Um, but I-I--
你只需当兼职来做
You'd only work part-time.
衣服给你员工特价
You'll get employee discounts on the clothes.
如果我是在浪费口舌 趁早说
Stop me if I'm wasting my breath.
我不知道 你怎么想 米奇尔
Well, I don't know. What do you think, Mitchell?
我 我会想念有你在家的日子
Well, I-I would miss having you around the house,
但你知道的 要是 要是你真心喜欢
But, you know, if--if it's something that you love...
我想想
Mulling.
这样吧 你主动提供工作真是太好了
You know what? It was nice of you to offer,
-但他或许还会再想想 -我接受了
- But he should probably think about it. - I'll do it!
真的吗
Really?
是的 直到他找到人来换我
Yep. Just until he can find somebody to replace me,
祝你好运
and good luck with that.
对了 别让我叠衣服
Oh, and I don't fold.
郎吉 我要去喝杯蛋白质奶昔
Longe, I'm getting a protein shake.
好的 米奇尔 这是侨
Okay. Mitchell, this is Jeoux.
你好 就光是"乔"吗
Hi. Oh, just "Joe"?
是的 侨 单人旁+乔
Yes, Jeoux. J-e-o-u-x.
懂了
There it is.
他就是你要帮的那位米奇吗
Oh, is this the Mitchell you're helping out
因为他希望自己的男朋友找份工作
Because he wants his boyfriend to get a job?
我不懂你们在干嘛 我也得挥吗
I don't know what you're doing. Should I wave?
你男朋友接受这份工作了吗
Did your boyfriend take the job?
天呐 这件衬衣你穿真好看 小卡
Oh, my god! That looks so good on you, Cam!
想都别想
Don't even.
我现在是强忍着不和你当众吵
It is everything I can do to not create a scene right now.
你会付出代价的[付钱]
You will pay for this. Mnh.
以及这个
And this.
还有这个
曼尼 你怎么看起来不太高兴啊
Manny, you don't seem so happy.
你以前很喜欢
You usually love
我带你"挑学"出来打曲棍球的啊
when I pull you out of school to play hockey.
首先 那叫"逃学"
"A," It's "Hooky,"
其次 别再带我逃学去打曲棍球了
And "B," Don't ever take me out of school to play hockey.
学校里发生什么事了吗
Did something bad happen at school?
音乐老师被解雇了
They fired the music teacher.
希迪奥·纳玛奇老师吗
Mr. Hideo Namagachi?
你说这个倒是很溜
That you say perfectly.
曼尼 别担心 他会找到新工作的
Manny, don't worry. He'll find another job.
但我怎么办
What about me?
多年来我拼命拍着纳玛奇老师的马屁
I've been buttering up Mr. Namagachi for years.
他终于打算让我当学校音乐剧的主唱了
He was gonna give me the lead in the school musical,
《雾都孤儿》呢
"Oliver!"
现在还没结束呢
Is it not all over.
是《雾都孤儿》
"Oliver!"
曼尼
Manny...
你是个很有才华的男孩
You are a very talented boy.
你会找到一大堆音乐老师
You're gonna find plenty of music teachers
继续你的马屁事业
to put butter on.
如果我找不到怎么办 我可不想
But what if I can't? I don't want
中学最后一年还得在合唱队混
to spend my last year of middle school in the chorus.
也许我能帮上忙
Maybe I can help.
也许当他们找好新的音乐教师后
Maybe when they pick the new music teacher,
我可以和他小调一下情
I'll go and I'll flirt a little bit with him.
妈 既然我们只是随便聊聊天
Hey, mom, since we're just talking here,
关于你的上衣
About your shirt.
我的上衣怎么了
Uh-- what about my shirt?
没什么
Nothing.
我只是看见上面沾了点
I just noticed you got some, uh,
沾了点披萨 就沾在了冰淇淋的那地儿
Some pizza... on the ice cream on it.
这儿的一小块
Ah, a little piece of-- mm.
想要知道宝宝的性别是很自然的啊
It's natural to want to know the sex.
那涉及到实际性的问题 育婴室该刷成什么颜色
And there's practical matters-- how you paint the nursery.
歌洛莉亚应该
Gloria should--
-菲尔 别抖了行不 -什么
- Phil, would you please knock that off? - What?
-你怎么了 紧张吗 -我才不紧张
- What's the matter? Are you nervous? - I'm not nervous.
可 可能是你在紧张
May-maybe you're the one who's nervous.
你想过这没
You ever think about that?
-好吧 -"紧张"
- Okay. - "Nervous."
因为如果你改变了主意的话
Because if you've had a change of heart...
我才没改变主意
I haven't had a change of heart.
或许是你改变了主意 我激动着呢
Maybe you had a change of heart, but I'm totally pumped.
激动 激动 超级激动
Pump, pump, pumped.
活力四射 我鼓鼓的 踢腿
Pump up the jam in my pumped-up... kicks.
鼓的 矮胖的 又矮又胖的
Pumpty-dumpty. Pumplestiltskin.
因为他们总做这样的手术
Because they do this kind of thing all the time,
用不了一小时
and in about an hour,
你就又会想"骑马"奔腾了
you're gonna be wanting to ride a horse.
邓菲先生 请到前台来
Mr. Dunphy, can you please come to the desk?
你打算怎样 菲尔
What's the plan, Phil?
坐着 我就打算坐着
Just sit here. I'm just gonna sit--
坐一会儿 好好坐着
I'm gonna sit a bit. Sitting pretty.
有没有叫菲尔·邓菲的
Is there a Phil Dunphy here?
我是他的岳父 他得等一会儿
I'm his father-in-law. He's gonna need a moment.
有没有什么东西需要我替他填写的
Is there anything I could fill out for him?
没有 除非你也想做结扎
Not unless you want the vasectomy.
半年前你死哪儿去了
Where were you six months ago?
巴巴多斯 我现在要和患者讲话
Barbados. Now I really need to speak with the patient.
明白 菲尔 过来
Got it. Phil, get over here.
菲尔
Phil?
他刚跑外...
He just ran ou--
你知道什么能让你们生意兴隆吗
You know what could do wonders for your business here?
术后休息室
A recovery room.
等等 等下 我不太想这样
Okay, wait, wait. I'm not sure about this.
别孩子气了
Don't be a baby.
会很酷的 别乱动
It's gonna look cool. Just hold still.
妈 你怎么在家
Mom, what are you doing here?
我要换衣服 你怎么没上学
I am changing my shirt. Why aren't you at school?
邓菲太太我们刚才
Mrs. Dunphy, we just--
没你说话的份儿 莫蒂莎
Oh, no, you don't get to talk, Morticia.
我们翘了最后一节课 挺大事哈
Okay, we cut last period-- big deal--
因为我们要剃脖子后面的毛发
because we're shaving the backs of our necks,
那超级时尚有型的
which is totally a style.
当然了 你现在又要发疯了
But of course now you're going to freak out
-就像你对待每一件小事那样 -剃吧
- like you always do about every little thing. - Let's do it.
-什么 -没错 我们来剃剃头吧
- What? - Yeah. Yeah. Let's shave up some heads.
来吧 谁先来
Come on. Who's first?
行了 老妈 我们不用你做这个
Uh, okay. Okay, mom, we-- we don't need you to do that.
-你害怕了吗 -我没有
- Are you afraid? - I'm not afraid!
那就来啊 剃头时间到
Then let's do this. It's shaving time.
剃肉横流 剃离苦海
Shavy gravy. Shaved by the bell.
你说话怎么跟爸爸似地
Why are you talking like dad?
头发扎起来 姑娘们
Hair up, girls!
后脖颈子露出来 来啊 来
Let's see some napes. Come on. Let's--
天啊 不
Oh, god. No!
-我的天 我的天呐 -你做了什么
- Oh, my god! Oh, my god! - What did you do?!
你做了什么 我周六要参加我姐婚礼呢
What did you do? I have my sister's wedding on Saturday!
真是对不起
I'm so sorry.
斯凯勒 等等
Uh, Skylar, wait!
我 我可以替你剪得再整齐一点
I could--I could-- I could even that up for you.
你们母女俩都离我远点儿
Stay away from me, both of you!
你把我的生活毁了
Uhh! You ruined my life!
斯凯勒
Skylar!
小卡
Cam.
卡梅隆 你总得跟我谈谈呐
Cameron! Ohh! You're gonna have to talk to me at some point!
好吧 容我先把这事写到日程表上
Oh, well, let me put that on my list of things to do,
-就在"找工作"下边 -你能不能别跑
- right after "Get a job." - Would you stop running away?
不能
Nope.
小卡 拜托
C-Cam! Come on!
我现在都追不上你了
You know, I can barely catch up with you
因为你比以前瘦了好多
Now that you lost all that weight.
知道吗 我现在睡眠也好了
You know what? I am sleeping better,
精力也充沛了 好啊 你行
and I do have more energy-- oh, you know what? You're good.
你真行
You're very good.
小卡 我之所以想要你去做那个工作
Cam, the only reason I tried to get you that job
是因为我觉得你有那么一点点空虚
is because you've been seeming a little... unfulfilled.
所以呢 你觉得把我
Oh, what, and you thought you'd fix me
变成导购小姐就好了吗
by turning me into some common shopgirl?
你不能走 我们还有女儿
You're not going anywhere. We have a daughter.
不是我走 是你走
It's not for me. It's for you.
小卡 我不走 都打包好了
Cam, I'm not go-- okay, well, that's packed.
没错 要是你打算去个寒冷的地方
Yeah, and if you're going someplace cool,
我还打包了一个冬季版的
I have a winter one packed as well.
不 我哪儿也不去
No, I'm not going anywhere!
而且我要跟你把这些事情说清楚
And I should be able to talk to you about these things.
说什么说
Oh, what things?
说我的生活有多空虚吗
How empty my life is?
你根本不知道我每天
You know, you have no idea what I do
为这个家都做了什么 我买食材
around this house every day. I shop for food,
我付账单 我收拾屋子
I pay the bills, I maintain the house,
我去食杂店
I grocery shop.
跟买食材是一回事
Same as shopping for food.
我还要忙活我的大项目
And still I have enough time to work on my master project.
而且你从来不问人家的大项目是什么
And you never ask me what my master project is.
是你让我别问的嘛
Because you told me not to ask!
好吧 既然你不肯善罢甘休
Fine, since you won't let it go...
这个
Does this...
看着像是一个空虚的懒鬼干的活儿吗
look like the work of an unfulfilled slacker?
人鱼装
A mermaid costume?
我亲自设计 手工缝制的
Hand-sewn from my own design.
你缝过莱卡面料的东西吗
Have you ever stitched lycra?
像在水中穿针引线一样 米奇尔
It's like sewing water, Mitchell.
貌似莉莉穿有点小
It looks a little small for Lily.
不是给莉莉穿的
It's not for Lily.
是给小猫穿的
It's for the cat.
是有人替小猫做人鱼装的
It's a mermaid costume for the cat.
这就是我的大项目
My master project.
这个人鱼装是
It's a mermaid costume...
给猫穿的
for a cat!
好了 别哭了
Okay. Hey, don't cry, okay?
不 挺漂亮的 这个
No, no, it's--it's nice. It's--
是非常漂亮的猫咪装
It's a very nice cat costume.
少来了
Oh, stop it!
这是我八个星期的人生啊
This is eight weeks of my life!
我愚蠢 空虚 诡异
My--my stupid, empty, creepy,
一无是处 给猫咪打扮的人生
useless cat-dressing life.
我给你拿纸巾 好吗
Let me get you a tissue, all right?
-这里 -好的
- Here. - Okay.
瞧你 还给我打包了纸巾
Oh! You packed me tissues.
我知道你过敏了会怎需要用到的
I know how you are with your allergies.
小卡 你知道我从来没觉得你懒
Cam! You know I don't think you're lazy.
我知道 那只是我对父亲的心结
I know. That's just stupid dad stuff.
我只是不喜欢农场的工作
You know, I didn't like working on the farm,
他就说那是因为我懒
and he just took it as me being lazy.
可事实是 我很空虚
The truth is, is I am unfulfilled.
我需要寻找目标
And I do need to find something.
你有挑战目标的时候看起来更开心
Well, you just--you seem happier when you have a challenge.
-知道吗 -我知道
- You know? - I know, I know.
我喜欢教孩子们音乐
You know, I loved teaching music to kids,
然后莉莉出现在我们的生命中
and then--then Lily, she came along, and...
照顾她是全世界最美妙的工作
That's the best job in the whole wide world.
知道吗 现在她不像从前那样需要我了
You know? And now she doesn't need me as much.
好啦 好啦
No, come on, come on.
我们再替你找目标 好吗
We're gonna find you something else, all right?
不一定得去朗吉娜的店
And it doesn't have to be Longinus.
-或者这个 -好的
- Or this. - Yeah.
其实 我真的很喜欢他家的衬衫
You know, I do like these shirts.
知道 知道
Yeah. Yeah.
我得想想
Mulling.
-好吧 -如果我真要想清楚
- Okay. - You know, if I'm gonna mull,
我得吃点巧克力
I could really use some chocolate.
因为你在节食 所以家里没存货
Well, since your diet, we don't keep it around the house.
-侧袋里 -是吗 真有
- Side pocket. - Yeah? Oh.
-提醒我补货 -好的
- Remind me to replace these. - Okay.
是你啊 杰 你好吗
Oh. Hey, Jay! How you doing?
菲尔 你不能这样遇事就逃跑
Phil, you gotta stop running from things because--
逃跑 我没在跑
Running? I'm not running.
-你才是在跑 -听着 我不会再兜个圈了
- You're running. - Look, I'm not up for another round with this.
快给我上车 我今天很不爽
Just get in the damn car! I'm not having a great day!
你今天不爽
You're not having a great day?!
你马上会像雪纳瑞犬一样被取掉卵巢吗
Are you about to get spayed like a common schnauzer?!
不是取掉卵巢 是输精管结扎 你是个爷们儿
They don't spay you, they fix you. You're a man!
我只想一直当个爷们儿
I just want to stay one!
菲尔 你到底怕什么
Phil, what's scaring you here?
怕人家觉得你不够爷们儿了吗
That people are gonna think less of you as a man?
不 我怕会很痛
No, I'm afraid it's gonna hurt.
-原来是这样啊 -慢着 人家会那么想吗
- That's what this is about? - Wait, people think that?
会觉得我不够爷们儿了吗
That you're less of a man?
我还没想到这点呢
That never even occurred to me.
听着 没人会就此看轻你
Look, no one's gonna think less of you.
而且根本不痛
And it hardly even hurts.
我下面非常敏感
I'm unusually sensitive down there.
有些按摩浴缸都不能用
I can't go in certain jacuzzis.
整个过程我都会陪着你的
I'm gonna be with you the entire way.
而且对疼痛的恐惧
Plus it's the fear of pain
总是比实际的疼痛要夸张得多
that's always more than the actual experience.
你说这话当然容易 你向来天不怕地不怕
That's easy for you to say. You're not afraid of anything.
-我当然也有害怕的 -说来听听
-Of course I'm afraid of stuff. - Like what?
听着
Look...
你还记得之前 我告诉你
You remember before, when I told you I was
我想知道 宝宝的性别
wanting to know the-- the sex of the baby...
为了处理好一些实际的问题 其实不是的
For practical matters? Well, that wasn't true.
我有些害怕生个女儿
I'm kind of afraid of having a girl.
少来了 这算什么问题
Give me a break. That's not a thing.
你只是更想要个儿子而已
You'd just rather have a boy.
大家都更想要儿子
Everyone would rather have a boy.
不 我是真害怕 我很了解男孩
No. I'm actually scared. I get boys.
只是女孩儿们 太复杂了
It's girls-- they're--they're complicated.
克莱尔童年的一半时间 我竭尽所能地
Half of Claire's childhood, I did everything I could
想将她变成男孩
to try to turn her into a boy.
无论你当年有什么心结
Well, whatever your issues were,
你和克莱尔现在很好啊
you and Claire are good now.
但我可能没那么多时间陪着
Yeah, but I may not get that kind of time
那个新出生的孩子 我不能搞砸了
with this new one, and I can't screw it up.
我不觉得自己体贴入微到可以养女儿
I don't think I'm sensitive enough to raise a girl.
杰 你现在就很体贴入微啊
Jay, you're being sensitive right now.
我都歇斯底里了 而你让我冷静了下来
I mean, I was pretty hysterical, and you calmed me down.
我觉得你和以前不一样了
I-I don't think you're the guy you used to be.
你这是在说 如果我能应付你
So you're saying that if I can deal with you,
我就能应付 其他任何一个小女孩
then I can handle... any other little girl?
我觉得你暗示我像小女孩一样是不合适的
I think I'd put it a-a little differently.
不 我觉得就是这样
No, I-I-I think that's right.
多谢了
Thanks.
要去做手术吗
We gonna do this?
向我保证不会那么痛
Promise it's not gonna hurt that much?
就像轻轻掐一下
Tiny, little pinch.
-我是自己吓自己 对吗 -绝对的
- I built it up in my head, didn't I? - Totally.
我依然可以拥有完全满足的...
And I can still achieve a-a full and satisfying...
知道吗 我们爷俩儿现在处的很不错
You know what? We had a nice little moment here.
这样的时候不多
We don't have many of those.
我要让这一刻永存
I think I'm gonna commemorate it.
-好的 -准备好了吗
- Okay. - All right?
坐直了
So sit up straight.
来拍一张
There you go.
别别 手臂放下 手臂放下好些
No, no, the arms down. Uh, better arms down.
没错 对对对
All right. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
就那样挺好 放松
That's right. Relax.
看这里
There you go.
完美
Perfect.
能洗一张给我吗
Can I get a copy?
会洗很多张的
Oh, there'll be a lot of copies.
太好了
Oh, great.
你对那个卖肉桂面包的家伙有些刻薄啊
You were kind of hard on that cinnamon bun guy.
你听到他对我说什么了吗
Did you hear what he said to me?
"恭喜"
"Congratulations"?
他看出我怀孕了
He thinks I'm pregnant!
那简直是对没有孕状的人的一种侮辱
That is an insult when the person doesn't look it.
妈 等一下
Mom, wait.
你得听我说
You need to hear this.
你怀孕了 而且显肚子了
You are pregnant, and you look it.
我希望肚子里的新宝宝能更懂礼貌些
I hope that this new one has some good manners!
妈 停下
Mom, stop!
我知道这一切对你来说有些可怕
I know this whole thing is a little scary for you.
你上次怀孕时 基本是一个人挺过来的
Last time you were pregnant, you kinda did it alone
因为爸爸不怎么在你身边
'cause dad wasn't around much.
但这次你有两个伴在身边
But this time you have two partners.
真甜蜜
That's sweet.
你也是个小甜心
And so are you.
特别是你脸上还沾着点糖
Especially with a little bit of sugar in your face.
我看看
Let me see.
怎么回事
Ohh! What happened?!
你的衣服实在是太小撑不住了
Your shirt couldn't take it anymore!
都怪那傻逼干洗员
The stupid dry cleaners!
它 它在哪儿
W-- where is it?!
不
Ay, no!
这下你真没辙了
Oh! You're running out of arms, mom!
那边正好有一家母婴店
A maternity store's right over there!
-那是什么 -我不知道 不过我们快走吧
- What was that? - I don't know, but let's go!
是你啊 我还以为给我剃毛的人来了呢
It's you. I thought it was the guy coming to shave me.
太好了 他们还没开始
Oh, good. They haven't started.
他的脖子上还有一小张草纸
He had a little piece of bloody toilet paper on his neck.
真叫人不安
It was disconcerting.
-你还好吗 -嗯
- Are you okay? - Mm-hmm.
不错 今天真是疯狂的一天
Yeah. I had a pretty crazy day,
但是 到最后很有趣
But it--it had an interesting ending.
而那只海龟200岁了
And this tortoise was 200 years old.
抱歉 老是讲我的旅行让你挺无聊吧
I'm sorry. I'm boring you with my trip.
不会啊 一点也不无聊
No, not at all.
你的热气球穿越了活火山
You hot-air-ballooned over an active volcano.
三星期前我在杰斐逊一路畅通
Three weeks ago I made every green light on Jefferson.
我一说就停不下来嘴
Couldn't stop talking about it.
-你发邮件给我说过了 -天啊
- You e-mailed me. - Oh, god.
妈妈把斯凯勒的头发给剃了 真搞笑
Mom shaved Skylar's head? That's hilarious!
下次她屈尊去学校上学时 就没那么好笑了
It's not gonna be so fun the next time she bothers to show up for school
你管她呢 你又不喜欢她
What do you care? You know you don't even like her.
我是不喜欢 斯凯勒太恐怖了
I don't. Skylar's awful.
妈妈其实帮了我个大忙
Mom actually did me a huge favor.
我的天啊 千万别跟她说
Oh, my God. Do not tell her that.
不然她又得没完没了
She will never shut up.
我知道 记得那次你承认你并不讨厌
I know. Remember when you admitted that you didn't hate
她拖你去看的詹姆斯·泰勒的演唱会吗
that James Taylor concert she dragged you to?
当时真受不了她 "我就说吧
She was unbearable! "I told you!
他真的是天籁之声啊"
He's got the voice of an angel!"
她真是够傻的
She's such a nerd.
但是我有点想她了
I kind of miss her, though.
亲爱的 我不想这样做
You know, honey, I don't want to do this
除非你真的准备好了
unless you are really ready.
我准备好了
I am ready.
-我不知道我是否准备好了 -我也是
- I don't know if I am. - Me, either.
你想再等等吗
You wanna wait?
再等个五年
Five more years?
我总把生活看作由许多道门组成
I've always seen life like a series of doors.
有时候你得选择你要穿过哪道门
Sometimes you get to choose the door you go through,
有时候你根本无从选择
Sometimes you don't get that choice.
但你还是得穿过去
But you still gotta walk through.
所以你可以去猛敲或者叫门
So you can either go kicking and screaming...
或者趾高气昂地穿过
or walk through with your head held high.
既然这次我无法选择我要穿越的门
And since I don't get to choose the door I'm about to go through,
我只祈祷生出个健康快乐的孩子
I just pray it's a healthy, happy kid.
男孩
And a boy.
亲爱的 来看看曼尼刚发给我的
Honey, look what manny just sent me.
等一会儿 好了
Hang on one sec. Okay.
-是不是有史以来最好笑的 -没错
- Is that the funniest thing ever? - Oh, yeah!
老天啊 米奇尔 快过来
Oh... oh, my gosh. Mitchell, come here.
快来看看克莱尔刚发给我们的
You have to see what Claire sent us.
好的 等等 就一会儿
Okay, wait. One--one second.
-好了 -有没有很好笑
- Okay. - Is that hilarious?
-好棒啊 -可怜的菲尔
- That's great! - Oh, Phil!
真难堪
Ay, this is embarrassing.
我真不放心
I don't know how comfortable I am
让这家伙教我们家孩子
with this guy teaching our kid.